[
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which of the below standards should be met before shipping any used refrigerant cylinders?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The Significant New Alternatives Policy (SNAP)",
      "Underwriters Laboratories ",
      "Department of Transportation "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-1"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "In case shipping used refrigerant cylinders, they must be:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above. ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Filled to no more than 80% of their capacity.",
      "Shipped upright.",
      "Shipped in a well-ventilated area"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-2"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which international treaty regulates the production and use of ozone-depleting substances like CFCS, HCFCs, halons, methyl chloroform, and carbon tetrachloride?",
    "correctAnswer": "Montreal Protocol ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Treaty of CFC ",
      "Vienna Convention Law ",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-3"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which of the below has a long-term effect due to the use and release of CFCs and HCFCs?",
    "correctAnswer": "The stratosphere",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Transportation",
      "Heating Equipment",
      "Water Supply"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-4"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Crop loss, eye diseases, and skin cancer have been linked to:",
    "correctAnswer": "Depletion of Stratospheric ozone",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Depletion of Stratospheric oxygen",
      "Depletion of Stratospheric chlorine monoxide",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-5"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "When chlorine reacts with ozone, it creates... ..and leaves behind an….molecule.",
    "correctAnswer": "Chlorine Monoxide, Oxygen",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Carbon, Chlorine",
      "carbon dioxide",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-6"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "This refrigerant has a GWP of \"1\" and has the same potential to contribute to climate change as carbon dioxide.",
    "correctAnswer": "R-1233zd",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "R-410A",
      "R-22",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-7"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "A refrigerant cylinder designed to hold recovered refrigerant has which color combination:",
    "correctAnswer": "grey body and yellow top",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "green body and blue top",
      "Red body and yellow top. ",
      "green body and grey top"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-8"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which type of refrigerant can be transferred or sold to another individual?",
    "correctAnswer": "Reclaimed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Disposed",
      "Recovered",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-9"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "The atom found in CFC and HCFC refrigerants that damages ozone in the stratosphere is",
    "correctAnswer": "Chlorine",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hydrogen",
      "Carbon",
      "Fluorine"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-10"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which of the below refrigerant is a CFC?",
    "correctAnswer": "R-12",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "R-410A ",
      "R-1233zd",
      "R-123"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-11"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "After recovering refrigerant from a sealed system, what gas should be used to pressurize or blow debris out of the system for leak checking?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nitrogen",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hydrogen",
      "Oxygen",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-12"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What are the functions performed by oil in the compressor?",
    "correctAnswer": "A and B both",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "lubrication ",
      "Seal the moving parts of a compressor",
      "Cooling"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-13"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "It is important to ensure that the refrigerant recovery cylinder is filled within. % of its capacity.",
    "correctAnswer": "80",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "40",
      "70",
      "55"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-14"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Refrigerant reusable containers must be hydrostatically tested, and date stamped every…....years.",
    "correctAnswer": "5",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "2",
      "6",
      "3"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-15"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "In a refrigerant system, the …............serves as the connection between the evaporator and the compressor.",
    "correctAnswer": "Suction Line ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Evaporation Line",
      "Liquid Line",
      "None of the Above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-16"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Why is it necessary to dehydrate a refrigeration system?",
    "correctAnswer": "To remove water and water vapor contaminating the system",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "To remove ice contaminates ",
      "To remove debris from the system ",
      "Remove water from a hydrostatic pressure test"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-17"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What are the consequences of leaving moisture in a refrigeration system still in operation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Create highly corrosive and toxic acids ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Freezes up",
      "Increases head pressure ",
      "None of the above "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-18"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What are the necessary steps before initiating an evacuation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Recover all refrigerant ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Install dryer ",
      "Install site glass",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-19"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What is the maximum number of refrigerants a recovery cylinder can store?",
    "correctAnswer": "One",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Three",
      "Four",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-20"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "The service manifold's center port is typically identified by a…........ hose.",
    "correctAnswer": "Yellow",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Blue",
      "Grey",
      "Green"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-21"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which refrigerant is used in appliances with very high pressure?",
    "correctAnswer": "R-503",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "R-500",
      "R-410A",
      "R-22"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-22"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "The chlorine in CFCs and HCFCs",
    "correctAnswer": "will not dissolve in water ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "will rain out of the atmosphere. ",
      "can be easily removed from the atmosphere",
      "is not harmful to the environment. "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-23"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which of the below is correct about the Significant New Alternatives Policy (SNAP) Program?",
    "correctAnswer": "EPA's program that identifies refrigerants with lower overall risks to human health and the environment",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      " Covers only CFC and HCFC refrigerants used in industrial process refrigeration. ",
      "Covers only CFC and HCFC refrigerants used in residential air conditioning.",
      "Relates to CFC and HCFC refrigerants used in commercial air conditioning"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-24"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "In which phase will the refrigerant be in the discharge line?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hot Vapor",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Cold Liquid",
      "Hot Liquid",
      "Warm Vapor"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-25"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What is the ASHRAE classification of slightly flammable substances?",
    "correctAnswer": "A2L",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "B",
      "A3",
      "A1"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-26"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Low-pressure systems have a pressure relief valve set at .... Psig",
    "correctAnswer": "15",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "10",
      "12",
      "8"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-27"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "…......in the stratosphere breaks down CFCs, which releases chlorine ions.",
    "correctAnswer": "Ultraviolet Radiation",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "X-radiation",
      "Gamma Radiation",
      "Infrared Radiation"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-28"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "How can you check a system for leaks?",
    "correctAnswer": "Evacuate the system and pull a vacuum on it ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Use water pressure ",
      "Pressurize with oxygen ",
      "Use a hydrostatic test "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-29"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What steps should be taken if the oil has been contaminated due to burnout?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the Above",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Conduct a deep vacuum before recharging ",
      "Install a permanent filter-drier ",
      "Triple evacuate the system "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-30"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Could you explain the difference between recovery and recycling?",
    "correctAnswer": "B&C",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "There is no difference ",
      "Recycle is to clean refrigerant for immediate reuse ",
      "Recover is to remove refrigerant in any condition from a system and store itin an external container"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-31"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which standard from below options should refrigerant recovery equipment meet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Certified and labeled by an EPA-approved equipment manufacturer ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "DOT standards and labeling",
      "CAA Approval",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-32"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Refrigeration technicians who violate the Clean Air Act may:",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Be fined",
      "Lose certification",
      "Appear in court"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-33"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "After 1995, which option below is correct for obtaining CFC refrigerant to service existing refrigeration appliances in the US?",
    "correctAnswer": "From recovery and recycling",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "From solvent conversion",
      "From European manufacturers",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-34"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "A reward of up to USD ….....may be given for information that leads to a penalty against a technician who intentionally vents refrigerants into the atmosphere.",
    "correctAnswer": "10000",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "5000",
      "8000",
      "15000"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-35"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which component changes low-pressure vapor to high-pressure vapor",
    "correctAnswer": "Compressor",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Evaporator",
      "Condenser",
      "None"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-36"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Usually, blended refrigerants should be charged",
    "correctAnswer": "As liquid",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "At very hight temperatures",
      "As vapor",
      "None"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-37"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Manifold gauge sets are color-coded with the high-pressure gauge in",
    "correctAnswer": "Red",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Yellow",
      "Grey",
      "Blue"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-38"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "When disposing of a disposable refrigerant cylinder, ensure that the internal pressure is reduced to.... psig.",
    "correctAnswer": "0",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "5",
      "8",
      "15"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-39"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Refrigerants cannot be called \"reclaimed\" unless they",
    "correctAnswer": "have been chemically analyzed, and the refrigerants meet the ARI-700 purity standard",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Are recovered using equipment less than 1 year old",
      "were properly processed in a reclaiming machine.",
      "none"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-40"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What are some of the most severe consequences of damaging the Earth's protective ozone layer?",
    "correctAnswer": "The incidence of skin cancer in humans is on the rise.",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "An increase in natural radioactivity",
      "Marine plant mutations",
      "An increase in volcanic activity."
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-41"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which is used to remove ice from a sight glass?",
    "correctAnswer": "An Alchohol Spray",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "R-11 refrigerant ",
      "Water",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-42"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Recovery equipment that relies on the refrigerant pressure within the appliance is considered ............",
    "correctAnswer": "System-Dependant",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Illegal",
      "Self-Sufficient",
      "Self-Contained"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-43"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "The most commonly used oil in stationary air conditioning systems with HFC-410a refrigerant is ..............",
    "correctAnswer": "Ester Oil",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Mineral Oil",
      "Alktlbenzene Oil",
      "None"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-44"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What do chlorofluorocarbon (CFC) and hydrofluorocarbon (HCFC frigerants have in common?",
    "correctAnswer": "It is important to recover both of them before opening appliances for servicing or disposing of them.",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "They have same normal boiling points",
      "They both contain Hydrogen",
      "They have identical ODP"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-45"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "The refrigeration system's compressor receives a …....as its input refrigerant.",
    "correctAnswer": "Superheated Vapor",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Subcooled Vapor",
      "Subcooled Liquid",
      "Liquid"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-46"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "What steps is the U.S. taking to protect the stratospheric ozone layer?",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Capturing and ultimately eliminating the use of chlorofluorocarbons",
      "Enforcing strict emission requirements on garbage incinerators",
      "Replacing coal-fired power plants for the production of electricity "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-47"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "The process of arefrigerant blend boiling or condensing over a range of mperatures at constant pressure is known as",
    "correctAnswer": "Temperature Glide",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Mixture Slump",
      "Pressure slide",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-48"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which refrigerant contains a CFC?",
    "correctAnswer": "R-12",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "R-404a",
      "R-152a",
      "R-410a"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-49"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-0",
    "question": "Which of the below is illegal?",
    "correctAnswer": "releasing any refrigerant during the service maintenance repair. or disposal of appliances except for de minimis releases.",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "manufacture or import HFC refrigerants into the U.S",
      "use CFC refrigerants",
      "Any of the Above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-0-50"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "Could you clarify the EPA's definition of a small appliance?",
    "correctAnswer": "Manufactured, charged, and hermetically sealed in a factory and contains five pounds or less of refrigerant",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Manufactured, charged, and hermetically sealed in a factory and contains fifteen pounds or less of refrigerant ",
      "Manufactured, charged, and hermetically sealed in a factory and contains two pounds or less of refrigerant",
      "None of the above "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-1"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "What is the most commonly used refrigerant to replace R-12 in new household refrigerators?",
    "correctAnswer": "R-134a",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "R-141a /141b blend",
      "R-123",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-2"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "Recovery equipment used for servicing or repairing small appliances must be certified by an EPA-approved laboratory if the equipment was manufactured after",
    "correctAnswer": "November 15,1993",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "May 15,1993 ",
      "June 15,1992 ",
      "July 15,1993 "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-3"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "What is the maximum amount of refrigerant allowed to be charged in Type I appliances at the factory?",
    "correctAnswer": "5 pounds",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "2 pounds",
      "3 pounds",
      "4 pounds"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-4"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "What are some possible causes of high pressure on the discharge side of an active self-contained recovery unit?",
    "correctAnswer": "B&C",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A closed recovery tank outlet valve",
      "A closed recovery tank inlet valve. ",
      "Excessive air or other non-condensable in the recovery tank"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-5"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "What refrigerants must be recovered with EPA-regulated equipment under section 608?",
    "correctAnswer": "R-12",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "R-134a",
      "R-123",
      "Sulfur Dioxide"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-6"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "In the event of a significant release of R-12 or R-22 in a contained area, what should you do?",
    "correctAnswer": "Self-contained breathing apparatus (SCBA) or leaving the area is required",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Respiratory protection is not required as these gases are not toxic. ",
      "Dust masks are sufficient protection against harmful vapors. ",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-7"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "The EPA requires appliances to have a service aperture when adding or removing refrigerant. For small appliances, this service port is typically..",
    "correctAnswer": "A piercing access valve can be used to enter the system through a straight piece of tubing known as a Process Tube.",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Located 15 inches below the compressor",
      "Installed at the factory and is 1/4 inch in diameter with machine threads ",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-8"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "When is it appropriate to use piercing valves, and what is a common issue with them?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fittings tend to leak over time and should not be left on appliances ",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Piercing valves are not allowed",
      "A closed recovery tank outlet valve",
      "B&C"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-9"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "CFCS will no longer be produced within the borders of the United States after",
    "correctAnswer": "1995",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1996",
      "1997",
      "2000"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-10"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "After November 15,1993, recovery equipment for small appliances must be capable of recovering",
    "correctAnswer": "B&C",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "99% of the refrigerant regardless of compressor operation and achieve a 10- inch vacuum under ARI 740-1993 ",
      "80% of the refrigerant when the compressor is not running or achieves a 4- inch vacuum under ARI 740-1993.",
      "90% of refrigerant when the compressor is operating or achieves a 4-inch vacuum under ARI 740-1993. "
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-11"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "Passive refrigerant recovery of small appliances, dependent on the System",
    "correctAnswer": "All of the above",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "It is important to recover refrigerant in a container that is not pressurized",
      "It is necessary to recover 80% of the refrigerant.",
      "It is not necessary to have a functioning compressor"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-12"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "Should the Clean Air Act (CAA) regulations be modified after technician obtains certification?",
    "correctAnswer": "It will be the technician's responsibility to learn and comply with future changes in the law",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The technicians must be retested and pass the exam with 84%. ",
      "The technician must take a new test to be recertified.",
      "B&C"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-13"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "If you have a small appliance that contains R-12, it is important to take proper steps before disposing of it",
    "correctAnswer": "Recover the Refrigerent",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Turn upside down",
      "Pressurize with Nitrogen",
      "All of these"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-14"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "When servicing small appliances, individuals recovering refrigerant must hold certification as a Universal Technician or a",
    "correctAnswer": "Type I Technician",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Type II Technician",
      "Core Technician",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-15"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "To work on small appliances manufactured after November 14,1993, a technician must hold which certification?",
    "correctAnswer": "A&B",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Universal",
      "Type 1",
      "Type 2"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-16"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "What is the ideal temperature to check for excess air in a cylinder?",
    "correctAnswer": "Room temperature before taking a pressure reading.",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "52F",
      "55F",
      "B&C"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-17"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "EPA regulations mandate the recovery of at least 80% of refrigerant from small appliances with non-operating compressors if the technician is using ...........",
    "correctAnswer": "either type of recovery unit",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "a system-dependent (passive) recovery unit",
      "a self-contained (active) recovery unit",
      "None of these"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-18"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "What should you do when removing refrigerant from a frost-free  refrigerator?",
    "correctAnswer": "turn on the defrost heater to vaporize any trapped liquid",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "heat the recovery cylinder to vaporize liquid refrigerant.",
      "pack ice around the evaporator to ensure maximum liquid is available.",
      "All of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-19"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "If exposed to high temperatures from open flames or hot metal surfaces, R-12 or R-22 can decompose into",
    "correctAnswer": "hydrochloric and hydrofluoric acids",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "sulfuric and phosphoric acids",
      "boric and chromic acids ",
      "None"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-20"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "When using a graduated charging cylinder, any refrigerant that is vented",
    "correctAnswer": "must be recovered",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "does not need to be recovered",
      "does not need to be recovered",
      "None of the above"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-21"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "How often must renew the EPA section 608 certification?",
    "correctAnswer": "Doesn't Expire",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "In 3 Years",
      "in 5 years",
      "4 years"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-22"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "Before beginning the recovery procedure, do not install and open a piercing access valve if the system is at...... psig",
    "correctAnswer": "0",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "5",
      "4",
      "1"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-23"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "It is an EPA regulation that anyone who opens an appliance for maintenance, service, orrepair must have at least one self-contained recovery machine available at their place of business. The only exception to this rule are persons working on:",
    "correctAnswer": "small appliances",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "High pressure appliances",
      "R-410a Systems",
      "None"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-24"
  },
  {
    "category": "Type-1",
    "question": "Piercing-type valves should only be used on which of the following types of tubing material",
    "correctAnswer": "B&C",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Iron",
      "Copper",
      "Aluminun"
    ],
    "difficulty": "medium",
    "type": "Multiple Choice",
    "tags": [
      "epa608"
    ],
    "id": "epa608-Type-1-25"
  }
]